<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>A blog about IT in Île-de-France region</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Station F</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming soon&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 01:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/stationf</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/stationf</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Paris-Saclay University</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike all the schools I mentioned here, Paris-Saclay University is not just a simple university, but a group of universities in Île-de-France Region specializing in many scientific fields. Paris-Saclay also brings together France’s largest technology hub and offers to French and international students world-renowned degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/parissaclay</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/parissaclay</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>AgoraNov</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded more than 16 years ago, AgoraNov is one of the largest incubators in Île-de-France and France with more than 300 incubated startups, including successful companies such as the advertising giant &lt;em&gt;Criteo&lt;/em&gt;, the doctor appointment management app &lt;em&gt;Doctolib&lt;/em&gt; or the world robotics giant &lt;em&gt;Aldebaran&lt;/em&gt; (now &lt;em&gt;SoftBank Robotics&lt;/em&gt;). The incubator is also sponsored by many universities and public companies around the country.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 15:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/agoranov</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/agoranov</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>EPITA</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering since 1984, EPITA is a private French engineering school located a few minutes from Paris, which offers several degree programs in English for international students, from Bachelor to Master.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/epita</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/epita</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>La Ruche</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;La Ruche (&lt;em&gt;hive&lt;/em&gt; in English) is a network of incubators dedicated to social innovation. Its action includes co-working, incubation, events, but also the establishment of large-scale partnerships allowing each actor or startup to give birth to his project or idea in the best conditions, be it at Paris, in the region or in the whole of France with different “hives”.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 02:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/laruche</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/laruche</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Ecole 42</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;École 42 is a French institution specialized in free and open courses without any prerequisites. During 2 to 5 years, the school trains hundreds of developers by proposing the &lt;em&gt;“self-study”&lt;/em&gt; learning method through dozens of projects and programming rushs (called &lt;em&gt;“pools”&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 17:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/ecole42</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ecole42</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>NUMA</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Not just an open space for entrepreneurs, NUMA is an international hub of more than 300 organizations, including CAC40 leaders and hundreds of startups. Training and follow-up are at the heart of NUMA’s philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 23:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/numa</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/numa</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sorbonne University</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Created from the merger of highly reputable universities UPMC and Paris Sorbonne, Sorbonne University is one of the biggest Parisian universities, with more than 55,000 students on its various campuses. The university offers several courses in computer science, in French or in English, for long or short periods.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 14:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/sorbonneuniversity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sorbonneuniversity</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>IncubAlliance</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Incubator of the &lt;a href=&quot;/parissaclay&quot;&gt;Paris-Saclay&lt;/a&gt; cluster since 2005, IncubAlliance’s main mission is to create bridges between startups, companies, labor and research experts within the Paris-Saclay campus, through support, training and hosting services for startups and education stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 21:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/incuballiance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/incuballiance</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Epitech</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Epitech (also called European Institute of Technology) is a private Computer Science School with multiple campuses around the world and in Europe. The school offers computer courses to international and exchange students.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/epitech</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/epitech</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Pépinière 27</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;With more than 100 startups incubated in a general and multi-disciplinary ecosystem, Pépinière 27 is a Parisian incubator offering both a flexible hosting and support services, but also a rich and inspiring infrastructure, like a natural greenhouse where knowledge flourishes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 15:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/pepiniere27</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pepiniere27</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Efrei</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Located only 15 minutes from Paris, Efrei is a general engineering school of digital technologies created almost 90 years ago. Efrei delivers a French engineering degree since 1957 and offers French and English courses to foreign students.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 08:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/efrei</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/efrei</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Startup42</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Founded in 2013 by &lt;a href=&quot;/epita&quot;&gt;EPITA&lt;/a&gt;, Startup42 is a “fast &amp;amp; serious” project accelerator designed to offer hacker teams with a good idea the skills and opportunities they need to become startup founders, create an impactful product and actually sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 20:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/startup42</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/startup42</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Isep</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just minutes from the Montparnasse Tower and train station, Isep is a private engineering school specializing in digital technologies (IT, electronics, multimedia, networks) and attached to the Catholic University of Paris. Isep offers different courses for international students over different periods (semester, year).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 19:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/isep</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/isep</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
