<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-22T00:26:51+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">RoadToIT</title><subtitle>A blog about IT in Paris Region</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Station F</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stationf" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Station F" /><published>2019-05-21T01:16:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-21T01:16:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/stationf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stationf">&lt;p&gt;Designed by Xavier Niel (creator of &lt;a href=&quot;/ecole42&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;), STATION F is the largest startup incubator in the world, with several thousand startups, dozens of programs and a presence of major US companies on campus. By far the most impressive and developed incubator !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 Incubator Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;STATION F&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Paris, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🔢 Startups incubated&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1000+ startups&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏰 Size&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;34 000 m²&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🛍 The &lt;em&gt;“Petit plus”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Fighters Program is offered free of charge for one year to entrepreneurs &lt;br /&gt;who have not completed a course in high schools.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stationf.co/apply/fighters/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fighters Program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : Free &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stationf.co/apply/founders/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Founders Program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : 195 €/month&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inaugurated in 2017 after 4 years of work, Station F is not only a large building hosting thousands of startups, it is also a building full of stories. Built in the 1930s, it was a freight hall belonging to SNCF, the French train company. For a long time, this building, called &lt;em&gt;Halle Freyssinet&lt;/em&gt;, thus served as professional hangars, until its acquisition in 2013 by investor Xavier Niel (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iliad.fr/en/&quot;&gt;Iliad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scaleway.com/en/&quot;&gt;Scaleway&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.free.fr&quot;&gt;Free&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/ecole42&quot;&gt;42&lt;/a&gt;) and the City of Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campus is &lt;strong&gt;amazing&lt;/strong&gt;. It is very well placed, close to public transport, restaurants, cinemas and housing. It covers 34 000 m² and hosts a start-up area of more than 3000 workstations, a market, 26 international support and acceleration programs, event spaces and several food courts. You will find hundreds of apartments just ten minutes from the campus, with all the necessary equipment for housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/stationf-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Station F HQ&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;A personal guided tour at STATION F for 'Road To IT' ✌️&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-place-to-be&quot;&gt;The place to be&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to be honest: the first time you go to Station F, you are immediately impressed. Why ? Because you will not only find startups still unknown, but also what they call &lt;em&gt;Mentorship Offices&lt;/em&gt;. These are individual or small group sessions with a manager (engineer, commercial, developer, design) of a large company, such as Google, Apple, Amazon Web Services (AWS) or even OVH. They are here only to help you understand how their services work and how you can make the most out of their solutions, and it’s clearly something unique !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for something more advanced? Introducing Station F’s programs. There are currently two, and in truth they are exactly the same, with only one difference : the price. You will probably ask yourself (and you are right) why pay a program 195 € per month when you can get it for free ? The answer is in the name of the free program : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fighters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Fighters Program provides free access to the Founders Program for killer entrepreneurs who simply have not had the same opportunities as the rest.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the program is intended for entrepreneurs who have not had the chance to pursue higher education or to obtain a degree in business school or engineering. It’s open to everyone no matter where you come from. I thought it was important to talk about this program which I consider very innovative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, back to basics. Station F offers shared or closed offices (open all the time), an access to all restaurants/bars/cafeteria, but also to meeting rooms, Wi-Fi/LAN, printers, exclusive events with other high-level entrepreneurs and a tons of perks. In addition to this, you will find essential services and stuffs for startups : investment funds areas, a fab lab, 3D printers and public services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was in Ireland, a lot of people asked me if paying the monthly fee was the only way to join Station F, well… the answer is no. And you will understand why. ⬇️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/stationf-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Station F HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;power-to-entrepreneurs&quot;&gt;Power to entrepreneurs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An incubator would be nothing without its network of professionals, companies and entrepreneurs around the world, and Station F understood this from the beginning. In addition to the programs I presented above, Station F offers hundreds of programs designed with its partners, including digital leaders like Facebook and its &lt;em&gt;Facebook Garage Paris&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partner programs evolve over time and are often short-term programs. But it’s a great way to join the world of startups by being fully accompanied by an expert. The &lt;em&gt;Facebook Garage&lt;/em&gt; Program is a great example, it’s a six-month program for startups whose value proposition comes from the use of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We work with innovative startups in Paris. We support their business models and help bring about better data protection processes.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; – Facebook France&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, Facebook provides to these companies a mentoring and regular follow-up during the incubation period. This translates into workshops with Facebook teams, monthly meetings with managers and experts, and tips for quick professionalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Facebook is not the only company offering this program, you will find hundreds of programs in different areas, such as communication (Havas Group, HEC, EDHEC), beauty-retail (L’Oréal, Veepee), video games (Ubisoft), media (TF1), finance (BNP Paribas), tech (Microsoft, Thales, Usine.IO) and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;💎 &lt;em&gt;Le +&lt;/em&gt; : If you go to Paris, what I can advise you is to plan a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stationf.co/visits/&quot;&gt;visit to Station F for free&lt;/a&gt;, you will not have access to all the HQ (confidentiality of projects) but it is a very cool experience, you will also discover the neighborhood and the proximity with other incubators (&lt;a href=&quot;/numa&quot;&gt;NUMA&lt;/a&gt;) or schools (&lt;a href=&quot;/epitech&quot;&gt;Epitech&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/efrei&quot;&gt;Efrei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/epita&quot;&gt;EPITA&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STATION F&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 5 Parvis Alan Turing &lt;br /&gt;75013 Paris &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;www.stationf.co/contact&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10505.094107737681!2d2.371345!3d48.8339211!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x541ecb63365de48!2sSTATION%20F!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1566754114644!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="incubators" /><summary type="html">Designed by Xavier Niel (creator of 42), STATION F is the largest startup incubator in the world, with several thousand startups, dozens of programs and a presence of major US companies on campus. By far the most impressive and developed incubator !</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paris-Saclay University</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/parissaclay" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paris-Saclay University" /><published>2019-05-13T14:56:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-13T14:56:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/parissaclay</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/parissaclay">&lt;p&gt;Unlike all the schools I mentioned here, Paris-Saclay University is not just a simple university, but a group of universities in Île-de-France Region specializing in many scientific fields. Paris-Saclay also brings together France’s largest technology hub and offers to French and international students world-renowned degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 School Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Université Paris-Saclay&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Saint Aubain, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;⚖️ Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Community of universities and institutions (Comue)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;📆 Course Duration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 to 8 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;👥 Members&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CNRS, CEA, IHES, INRA, INRIA, ONERA, INSERM, AgroParisTech,&lt;br /&gt; CentraleSupélec, ENS, Université Paris-Sud and more&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Depends on courses, some institutions charge fees&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot compare the Paris-Saclay University with other schools because the concept is unique in France. Paris-Saclay brings together some ten universities and scientific institutions among the most renowned in the world. In order to synthesize the article as much as possible, I will present only the main courses offered in the field of computer and new technologies, and the student life in Paris-Saclay’s campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/parissaclay-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paris-Saclay campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;masters-degrees-fully-in-english&quot;&gt;Master’s degrees fully in English&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of all the masters offered by Paris-Saclay Université and its partners is very long, I propose below a presentation of the main masters in English of the Computer Science department (member of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/masters-degrees-in-english&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;School Engineering, information science and technology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; department)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m1-computer-science-international-track#presentation-m1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M1 Computer science - International track&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by Telecom Paris-Sud) 
&lt;br /&gt;Introduction to networks, human-computer interaction and computer science, with two majors : &lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-informatique-pour-les-reseaux-de-communication-computer-science-for&quot;&gt;Computer Networks (CCN)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-interaction-human-computer-interaction-hci&quot;&gt;Human Computer Interaction (HCI)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m1-hcid-eit-digital&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M1 Human Computer Interaction &amp;amp; Design - EIT Digital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by Université Paris-Sud)
&lt;br /&gt;Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction and Interactive Systems, with opportunities to choose from majors like IoT, mobile interaction, creative design, audio synthesis, virtual humans, AR and more.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-hcid-eit-digital#presentation-m2&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M2 Human Computer Interaction &amp;amp; Design - EIT Digital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by Université Paris-Sud)
&lt;br /&gt; Following M1 above, M2 HCID focuses on the design, development and evaluation of interactive systems that are adapted to users and the context of their use (gestural, mobile, AR/VR, intelligent agents, virtual humans, computer graphics and machine learning).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-reseaux-de-communications-avances-advanced-communication-networks-acn#presentation-m2&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M2 Advanced Communication Networks (ACN)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by Telecom ParisTech and Polytechnique)
&lt;br /&gt; Understanding network paradigms, architectures, algorithms and technologies, and win a strong expertise in theoretical tools and methods for network performance study and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-informatique-pour-les-reseaux-de-communication-computer-science-for#presentation-m2&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M2 Computer Science for Communication Networks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by Telecom Paris-Sud)
&lt;br /&gt;Introduction to practical and theoretical research in networks and computer science. It gives students the opportunity to deepen their technical knowledge through computer science methodologies applied to communication networks as well as to discover new emerging research topics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-data-knowledge-d-k&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M2 Data &amp;amp; Knowledge (D&amp;amp;K)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by LRI and Telecom ParisTech)
&lt;br /&gt;Introduction to web data management, knowledge &amp;amp; semantics, big data, artificial intelligence, and data analytics from a semantic point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-modeles-et-technologies-pour-le-decisionnel-decision-support-and-business&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M2 Decision Support and Business Intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by CentraleSupélec)
&lt;br /&gt;This Master’s program aims to provide the key elements required to meet these challenges that are: machine learning, visualization analytics, decision modeling,  graph data management and analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/education/master/m2-interaction-human-computer-interaction-hci&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;M2 Human Computer Interaction (HCI)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (by Université Paris-Sud and LRI)
&lt;br /&gt;This master provides students with fundamental knowledge and advanced techniques to design, develop and evaluate interactive systems that are adapted to the needs of their users. It trains specialists in Human-Computer Interaction and prepares them to careers in academia, industrial R&amp;amp;D and any company that develops interactive systems.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are comfortable with French (&lt;em&gt;et c’est une excellente chose !&lt;/em&gt;), Paris-Saclay University also offers masters in French &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; English, you will find the list and a detailed presentation on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/master-degrees-taught-in-french-and-english&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/parissaclay-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Paris-Saclay campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;campus--student-life-at-paris-saclay-university&quot;&gt;Campus &amp;amp; Student Life at Paris-Saclay University&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris-Saclay is probably the biggest hub of clubs in France, with more than 600 student organizations on the main campus. With many students, the University also offers housing solutions with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crous-versailles.fr/en&quot;&gt;Versailles’ CROUS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heberjeunes.fr/en/&quot;&gt;Héberjeunes&lt;/a&gt;. From 2018, 5000 new students’s residences will be built. Accommodation would be of different types and would represent a surface area of around 27 hectares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RER B (a regional train) goes directly to the university. In 2024, the &lt;em&gt;Grand Paris&lt;/em&gt; (Metro Line 18) project will enable nine identified areas (including Paris-Saclay) to be served, all of which represent economic development centers, bringing together companies, institutions and university and research establishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;International Relation Service&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guillaume GARRETA&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Director of International Development  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;guillaume.garreta@universite-paris-saclay.fr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d42126.02946861107!2d2.1175044791015556!3d48.70783489999999!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x47e67f6794d18479%3A0xf281f304394e3a1c!2sUniversit%C3%A9+Paris-Saclay!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1566146063955!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="schools" /><summary type="html">Unlike all the schools I mentioned here, Paris-Saclay University is not just a simple university, but a group of universities in Île-de-France Region specializing in many scientific fields. Paris-Saclay also brings together France’s largest technology hub and offers to French and international students world-renowned degrees.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AgoraNov</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/agoranov" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AgoraNov" /><published>2019-05-06T15:20:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-05-06T15:20:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/agoranov</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/agoranov">&lt;p&gt;Founded more than 16 years ago, AgoraNov is one of the largest incubators in Île-de-France and France with more than 300 incubated startups, including successful companies such as the advertising giant &lt;em&gt;Criteo&lt;/em&gt;, the appointment doctor management app &lt;em&gt;Doctolib&lt;/em&gt; or the world robotics giant &lt;em&gt;Aldebaran&lt;/em&gt; (now &lt;em&gt;SoftBank Robotics&lt;/em&gt;). The incubator is also sponsored by many universities and public companies around the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 Incubator Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AgoraNov&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Paris, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏰 Size&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2000 m²&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🔢 Startups incubated&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;320+ incubated projects and 300+ startups created&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🛍 The &lt;em&gt;“Petit plus”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AgoraNov has incubated successful companies like &lt;br /&gt;Criteo, Biophytis, Aldebaran, Doctolib and more.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NC&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key player in the entrepreneurship and innovation sector and launched 16 years ago, AgoraNov is a public incubator of startups with a strong technological identity. The incubator was founded by the UPMC University (now &lt;a href=&quot;/sorbonneuniversity&quot;&gt;Sorbonne University&lt;/a&gt;, do not hesitate to read my full article about it), Paris-Dauphine University, ENS, ParisTech and INRIA – and fully supported by the Ministry of Research and Higher Education, the Île-de-France Region, the City of Paris and the European Social Fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In less than 20 years, AgoraNov has raised more than 500 million euros of private funds for more than 320 incubated projects and 300 companies in the areas of digital technology, healthcare, industry and “greentech”. On the 320 incubated projects, nearly 170 have been rewarded by the Ministry of Higher Education and Research of France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agoranov simultaneously supports some 60 startups that benefit from personalized support, the possibility of being hosted in the heart of Paris, an acceleration program and the expertise of a community of more than 300 startups, including some “pépites” like Criteo and Doctolib.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/agoranov-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AgoraNov HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-very-selective-and-condensed-program&quot;&gt;A very selective and condensed program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the particularities of AgoraNov compared to its competitors is the very strong selection at the entrance with only 60 projects incubated per year over a period of 24 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join AgoraNov, you have to fill out a very complete form presenting your project. The form will  be validated or not by the AgoraNov team, you will then have to present your project to the Incubator Expert Committee and if your project is accepted, an agreement is signed between AgoraNov and your team. You will understand that an Olympic preparation is necessary to join AgoraNov !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/agoranov-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;AgoraNov HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-agoranov-bring-&quot;&gt;What does AgoraNov bring ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AgoraNov program is specific to each company and each domain (hopefully) but in general, the incubator will bring personality coaching by an experienced team from different fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this you will also have accommodation with closed or open offices in the heart of Paris, you will have an infrastructure of more than 2000m², including meeting rooms, open-spaces, workspaces, relaxation areas and a reception.
You will of course be able to exchange with other companies present on the spot and benefit from targeted training sessions (meetings with partners, investors, industrialists or experts of the sector).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We have an appetite for more technological projects, but as we are open to all sectors, it creates synergies between web start-ups and those that are more tech”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; - David Argellies, Chargé d’affaires at AgoraNov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If AgoraNov is distinguished from others by being a public incubator, it’s also a real creator of “French pépites” - these successful companies that we see more and more in our lives. And that’s just the beginning !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le +&lt;/em&gt; : For the past few years, AgoraNov has been involved in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesstartupsalecole.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Startups at School”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project, which aims to bring school audiences and young innovative companies closer together in the context of educational projects conceived in various school subjects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AgoraNov&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 96bis Boulevard Raspail &lt;br /&gt;75006 Paris&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;courrier@agoranov.com&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;+ 33 (0)1 44 18 07 15&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10502.619193341674!2d2.3283103!3d48.8457229!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0xd90298e3baae58f8!2sAgoranov!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1566482519662!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="incubators" /><summary type="html">Founded more than 16 years ago, AgoraNov is one of the largest incubators in Île-de-France and France with more than 300 incubated startups, including successful companies such as the advertising giant Criteo, the appointment doctor management app Doctolib or the world robotics giant Aldebaran (now SoftBank Robotics). The incubator is also sponsored by many universities and public companies around the country.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EPITA</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/epita" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EPITA" /><published>2019-04-29T10:18:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-29T10:18:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/epita</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/epita">&lt;p&gt;Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering since 1984, EPITA is a private French engineering school located a few minutes from Paris, which offers several degree programs in English for international students, from Bachelor to Master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 School Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;École pour l’Informatique et les Techniques Avancées (EPITA)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kremlin-Bicêtre, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;⚖️ Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Private Engineering School&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;📆 Course Duration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;18 months to 3 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🇪🇺 Erasmus Students&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Accepted&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;≈ 9000€/year + fees&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created in 1984, EPITA (School for Computer Science and Advanced Techniques) is an engineering school located in Île-de-France Region, specialized in Computer Science. The school offers various degree programs for international students, which can mingle with French students (of which I am a member) on the main campus located in Kremlin-Bicêtre, just a few minutes from Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main campus is made up of different buildings and many rooms with computers of last generations (Linux and macOS). Campus is shared with another school, Epitech, a computer school that offers IT degree. I invite you also to read Epitech’s presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPITA offers 4 degree programs for international students : a Bachelor of Computer Science (BCS), two Masters of Science (in Computer Science and AI Systems) and a Master of Computer Engineering. In addition to these courses, EPITA also offers boot camps and entrepreneurship short programs and joint &amp;amp; dual degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/epita-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EPITA campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-wide-range-of-specialization&quot;&gt;A wide range of specialization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During your studies, you will be able to choose majors, such as Global IT Management, Software Development, Project management, Advanced Algorithms, IoT, Networks &amp;amp; Security and more. You will also attend general courses in the early years, such as algorithmic, linear algebra, thermodynamic physics, computer architecture and electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EPITA is a school that allows everyone to discover computing through workshops and multiple projects. Every student can find or discover a new passion, whether it’s about security or project management.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
– Samy Hussaein, EPITA 4th year Student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/epita-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EPITA campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-very-active-student-life&quot;&gt;A very active student life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Life is very active in the main campus, with more than 70 clubs and organizations, like video games, programming, movies club and more. Only a few minutes from public transport, you can easily reach the center of Paris and nice places. &lt;em&gt;Le +&lt;/em&gt; : The Val-de-Marne department offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.valdemarne.fr/a-votre-service/deplacement/transports/remboursement-de-la-carte-imagine-r&quot;&gt;refund of part of your transport costs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, as a part of your final semester, you will have to do an internship. Paris and surrounding cities host many startups and large companies, like Apple, Google, Microsoft and Facebook. The French Tech is also a great way to discover new French startups with great potential, like in the incubator &lt;a href=&quot;/stationf&quot;&gt;Station F&lt;/a&gt;, just ten minutes from the EPITA campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;International Relation Service&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rabih HADDAD&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Director of International Programs &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;rabih.haddad@epita.fr&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;+33 (0)1 80 51 71 37&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10508.92156903637!2d2.3628171!3d48.8156654!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x581b7c8cd0a77c3e!2sEcole+d%E2%80%99ing%C3%A9nieurs+en+informatique+-+EPITA!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1565021285281!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="schools" /><summary type="html">Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering since 1984, EPITA is a private French engineering school located a few minutes from Paris, which offers several degree programs in English for international students, from Bachelor to Master.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">La Ruche</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/laruche" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La Ruche" /><published>2019-04-22T02:15:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T02:15:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/laruche</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/laruche">&lt;p&gt;La Ruche (&lt;em&gt;hive&lt;/em&gt; in English) is a network of incubators dedicated to social innovation. Its action includes co-working, incubation, events, but also the establishment of large-scale partnerships allowing each actor or startup to give birth to his project or idea in the best conditions, be it at Paris, in the region or in the whole of France with different “hives”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 Incubator Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;La Ruche&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Paris - Saint-Germain-en-Laye, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏰 Size&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3200 m²&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🔢 Startups incubated&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;125 projects per year&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🛍 The &lt;em&gt;“Petit plus”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;La Ruche offers an incubation program for women in tech, &lt;br /&gt;called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.les-audacieuses.org&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Les Audacieuses”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.les-ambitieuses.tech&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tech for Good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Starting at 145€/month&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched 11 ago with the conviction that a responsible and collaborative society was possible, La Ruche offers a range of services for entrepreneurs and young startups, from incubation to growth through advice and co-working spaces in all France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/laruche-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;La Ruche HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-place-to-bee&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The Place to Bee”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Hackathons to half-day to several days trainings, La Ruche offers a range of support for entrepreneurs and startups. In 1 year, more than 125 projects were incubated with an 83% survival rate of incubated entrepreneurs in the first 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the workspaces, I will focus on HQs in Île-de-France and Paris Region, but La Ruche also has workspaces in &lt;a href=&quot;https://la-ruche.net/ruche/bordeaux/&quot;&gt;Bordeaux&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://la-ruche.net/ruche/marseille/&quot;&gt;Marseille&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://la-ruche.net/ruche/saint-nazaire/&quot;&gt;Saint-Nazaire&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://la-ruche.net/ruche/montpellier/&quot;&gt;Montpellier&lt;/a&gt; and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 3200m² dedicated to the positive economy and a terrace of more than 200m² in Paris, La Ruche welcomes project leaders driven by social entrepreneurship, digital technology and culture.
You find an astonishing diversity among co-workers, such as entrepreneurs, associations, employees, teleworkers, self-employed and intrapreneurs. Each category has its own tariff range adapted to its needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/laruche-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;La Ruche HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;programs-for-all&quot;&gt;Programs for all&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La Ruche offers special rates for everyone, and offers 5 programs :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closed offices&lt;/strong&gt; (starting 1k€/month) with offices for up to 20 people, with a commitment of 6 months and unlimited access.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full time program&lt;/strong&gt; (starting at 350€/month) with unlimited access, a fixed office for 1 person and a 3-month commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half time program&lt;/strong&gt; (starting at 235€/month) with an access 20 half-days (or 10 days per month), a fixed office for 1 person and a 2-month commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quarter time program&lt;/strong&gt; (starting at 145€/month) with an access 10 half-days (or 5 days per month), a fixed office for 1 person and a 2-month commitment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full time company program&lt;/strong&gt; (starting at 500€/month) with unlimited access and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups have free Internet, printer, an access to 9 meeting rooms, a 220m² terrace, a kitchen/sleep room, training sessions, an access to meeting-space for your public events and of course, national professionals from La Ruche’s network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le +&lt;/em&gt; : As a &lt;em&gt;Paris Innovation&lt;/em&gt; certified incubator by the Paris City Hall, startups located in La Ruche can apply for a funding with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economie.gouv.fr/entreprises/financez-votre-projet-innovant-grace-a-paris-innovation-amorcage&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris Innovation Amorçage&lt;/em&gt; funding program&lt;/a&gt;. Created to support the development of startups hosted in incubators labeled &lt;em&gt;Paris Innovation&lt;/em&gt;, it is aimed at any innovative project in the seed or development phase.
Do not hesitate to consult the &lt;a href=&quot;https://api-site.paris.fr/images/71646&quot;&gt;detailed presentation&lt;/a&gt; of this program and to contact, as the case may be, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bpifrance.fr/Contactez-nous/Direction-regionale-Paris&quot;&gt;Paris Regional Office of &lt;em&gt;Bpifrance Île de France&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La Ruche® Paris&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 24 Rue de l’Est &lt;br /&gt; 75020 Paris &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;paris@la-ruche.net&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;+33 (0)1 83 64 59 04&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10497.279555023!2d2.3934424!3d48.8711781!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x9637fb10c7b597f2!2sLa+Ruche!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1566395464386!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="incubators" /><summary type="html">La Ruche (hive in English) is a network of incubators dedicated to social innovation. Its action includes co-working, incubation, events, but also the establishment of large-scale partnerships allowing each actor or startup to give birth to his project or idea in the best conditions, be it at Paris, in the region or in the whole of France with different “hives”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ecole 42</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ecole42" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ecole 42" /><published>2019-04-15T17:13:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-15T17:13:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ecole42</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ecole42">&lt;p&gt;École 42 is a French institution specialized in free and open courses without any prerequisites. During 2 to 5 years, the school trains hundreds of developers by proposing the &lt;em&gt;“self-study”&lt;/em&gt; learning method through dozens of projects and programming rushs (called &lt;em&gt;“pools”&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 School Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;École 42, 42 School &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; 42&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Paris, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;⚖️ Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Self-study institution / Association&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;📆 Course Duration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 to 5 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🇪🇺 Erasmus Students&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Accepted&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Free&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created in 2013 by Xavier Niel (President &lt;a href=&quot;/stationf&quot;&gt;Station F&lt;/a&gt;) and Nicolas Sadirac (ex-Director &lt;a href=&quot;/epitech&quot;&gt;Epitech&lt;/a&gt;, École 42 is a French Computer Science institution that prepares students for the computer and code development professions.
By training young people from all horizons, École 42 intends to highlight the capacity of innovation and digital transformation of companies in France and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At École 42, there is no course and no teachers, it is only learning peer-to-peer (or self-study). There are no notes and everyone progresses at their own pace through dozens of projects (team or alone) as well as many programming rushes (inspired by the EPITA and Epitech “pool”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/42-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42 France campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;born-to-code&quot;&gt;“Born to code”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join École 42, no prerequisites are needed, but only a period of programming rush, called the “Piscine” (or pool) : It is an immersion in the world of coding, used to identify the most motivated students. During 1 month, you will be able to discover the different aspects of the school and its method of learning. Best thing ? You can sleep for free in the school during this period. 2 weeks after the end of the pool, you will receive your results telling you if you can join the school or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you succeed, the training will last from 2 to 5 years according to your choice of studies. The program at École 42 is divided into 2 main parts : the compulsory notions to be acquired for a permanent job as a developer, such as network or algorithmic, followed by a phase of improvement during which the student can discover the many facets of development (Security, Artificial Intelligence, Deep learning, AR/VR, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of your studies, École 42 does not give a state-recognized degree, as the school is not officially considered as school but more as a non-profit association. However, the expertise of developers from 42 is now recognized in many companies around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/42-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42 France campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-campus-open-all-the-time&quot;&gt;A campus open all the time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French campus of École 42 is located in the north of Paris, in a recent and well-equipped building. You will find dormitories, a canteen, food trucks, gaming areas, conference rooms and many machine rooms with computers (running macOS). The school currently has 9 clubs, including air-soft, training and sale of business services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, 42 France announced the expansion of the initial campus with the initiative &lt;em&gt;“Not A Campus”&lt;/em&gt; (NOC). This new campus will include club space, open-spaces, a collaborative grocery store, a fitness room, a student residence, green spaces and gardens (open to everyone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nota Bene&lt;/strong&gt; : Due to growing interest of the École 42’s method around the world, the school opened a second campus a few years ago, in the Silicon Valley (Fremont, CA). The philosophy is the same and if you are interested in the American campus, don’t hesitate to visit their website 42.us.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;International Relation Service&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;42 France&lt;/em&gt; does not offer specific contact, but I invite you to visit the admissions website : &lt;strong&gt;candidature.42.fr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10491.943364787661!2d2.318501!3d48.896607!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x4e808812dd36a382!2s42!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1565026855796!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="schools" /><summary type="html">École 42 is a French institution specialized in free and open courses without any prerequisites. During 2 to 5 years, the school trains hundreds of developers by proposing the “self-study” learning method through dozens of projects and programming rushs (called “pools”).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NUMA</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/numa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NUMA" /><published>2019-04-08T23:52:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-08T23:52:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/numa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/numa">&lt;p&gt;Not just an open space for entrepreneurs, NUMA is an international hub of more than 300 organizations, including CAC40 leaders and hundreds of startups. Training and follow-up are at the heart of NUMA’s philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 Incubator Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NUMA&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Paris, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🔢 Startups incubated&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🛍 The &lt;em&gt;“Petit plus”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NUMA offers a free open-space with bar on the ground floor&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Free co-working space &lt;br /&gt; Privatization of rooms from 1200€/day&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started in 2000 with &lt;em&gt;Silicon Sentier&lt;/em&gt;, an entrepreneur association with more than 180 partner companies. Their initial objective was to encourage meetings between entrepreneurs and to allow new projects to emerge and floor on the &lt;em&gt;Next Big Thing&lt;/em&gt;. The idea was to design a network capable of promoting and facilitating the development of entrepreneurship at the national level, and that’s what became NUMA today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NUMA is not only an open space for entrepreneurs or small businesses today, it’s a hub of more than 300 organizations, including CAC40 leaders and hundreds of startups - with a presence in Paris, Barcelona, Mexico, Toulouse, Berlin and even New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/numa-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NUMA HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-only-an-open-space&quot;&gt;Not only an open-space&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I went to NUMA, it was just to have a place where to discuss professionally with other students, entrepreneurs and business leaders. I discovered a free space co-working on the ground floor, with possibility to rent different rooms for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.numa.co/fr/reservation-de-salles&quot;&gt;private meetings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest surprise was to discover the “formations”. Today, the challenge is not only to master the technical aspect of a project but also the notions of management, “intrapreneurship”, design thinking and digital marketing. And guess what? That’s exactly what NUMA offers. In fact, we understand quickly that we do not invest only in a HQ or a place to work, but in a long-term support of your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/numa-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NUMA HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-infinity-and-beyond&quot;&gt;“To infinity and beyond”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the incubation program, NUMA brings its expertise to startups already on the market and having a consequent turnover, for 3.5 % equity participation.
NUMA’s philosophy is based on the development of the startups’ business and network, the implementation of a rigorous and effective methodology for executing their strategy as well as long-term support through a mentoring system with experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for something fun to do there, to discover the atmosphere of NUMA ? Do not hesitate to visit “La Cantine”, the first collaborative workspace created in Île-de-France Region, where many celebrities have passed to make conferences and exchange with members, like Mark Zuckerberg.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NUMA Paris&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 39 Rue du Caire&lt;br /&gt; 75002 Paris &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;+33 (0)1 40 13 64 40&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10498.002257592629!2d2.3497182!3d48.8677334!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x1715b707d5c6af5e!2sNuma+Paris!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1566312566704!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="incubators" /><summary type="html">Not just an open space for entrepreneurs, NUMA is an international hub of more than 300 organizations, including CAC40 leaders and hundreds of startups. Training and follow-up are at the heart of NUMA’s philosophy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sorbonne University</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sorbonneuniversity" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sorbonne University" /><published>2019-04-01T14:14:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T14:14:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sorbonneuniversity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sorbonneuniversity">&lt;p&gt;Created from the merger of highly reputable universities UPMC and Paris Sorbonne, Sorbonne University is one of the biggest Parisian universities, with more than 55,000 students on its various campuses. The university offers several courses in computer science, in French or in English, for long or short periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 School Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sorbonne Université&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Paris, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;⚖️ Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Public University&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;📆 Course Duration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 to 8 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🇪🇺 Erasmus Students&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Accepted&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;≈ 100€ (licence) to 601€/year (engineering master)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Present in the top 50 of the World’s Top Universities according to the 2019 Shanghai University Rankings, The Sorbonne University is also one of the most important scientific hubs in Paris with very important research structures : 136 research units including 66 of the Faculty of Science &amp;amp; Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorbonne University’s most important resource is it community of men and women who contribute to its missions through the diversity of their fields, the research they do and their personal and professional fulfilment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
– Ambassadors of Sorbonne University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students from all over the world come to Sorbonne University. They do this through Erasmus programs, international agreements, or by just applying directly for one of the degree programs. As this blog is dedicated to Computer Science and IT, you can discover the other courses offered by the University on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/sorbonne-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sorbonne campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-hub-with-scientific-programs&quot;&gt;A hub with scientific programs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three choices of studies are offered by Sorbonne University : A 3-year bachelor, a 2-year master and a 3-year doctorate (with special arrangements for medicine courses). Within the programs, you have the choice between different major and minor to be specialized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the IT programs you can find at Sorbonne University :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sciences.sorbonne-universite.fr/en/education/diplomas/sciences_and_technologies/bachelor_s_degrees/department_of_computer_science.html&quot;&gt;Bachelor’s in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; (French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sciences.sorbonne-universite.fr/en/international/international_programs/international_programs_for_master_degrees/eit-digital-master-school.html&quot;&gt;Master’s in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sciences.sorbonne-universite.fr/en/education/diplomas/sciences_and_technologies/masters/master_of_engineering.html&quot;&gt;Master’s in Engineering Sciences&lt;/a&gt; (English)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polytech.sorbonne-universite.fr&quot;&gt;Engineering Degree or &lt;em&gt;Diplôme d’ingénieur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (French and English)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Engineering Degree, the courses take place in Polytech, a French engineering school. Polytech delivers an engineering degree (equivalent to Master’s) accredited by the French commission of the title of engineer (CTI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During your studies, you will work on areas such as robotics (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/androide&quot;&gt;ANDROIDE&lt;/a&gt;), software (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/stl/&quot;&gt;STL&lt;/a&gt;), bioinformatics (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/bim/&quot;&gt;BIM&lt;/a&gt;), imaging (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/ima/&quot;&gt;IMA&lt;/a&gt;), computer networks (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/res/&quot;&gt;RES&lt;/a&gt;) and cyber-security (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/sar/&quot;&gt;SAR&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/sesi/&quot;&gt;SESI&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-master.ufr-info-p6.jussieu.fr/parcours/sfpn/&quot;&gt;SFPN&lt;/a&gt;).
Some international programs like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sciences.sorbonne-universite.fr/en/international/international_programs/international_programs_for_master_degrees/eit-digital-master-school.html&quot;&gt;Master’s in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; propose a double European master in English with a major in Computer science and a minor in Innovation (Cloud and Networks Infrastructure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for short studies, Sorbonne University’s Faculty of Science organizes several international &lt;a href=&quot;http://sciences.sorbonne-universite.fr/fr/international/universites_d_ete.html&quot;&gt;summer schools&lt;/a&gt; that are open to international students too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/sorbonne-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sorbonne campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-huge-campus-in-the-heart-of-paris&quot;&gt;A huge campus in the heart of Paris&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I went to the Sorbonne University’s main HQ (called &lt;em&gt;Jussieu&lt;/em&gt;) was a few years ago. At that time, they had just finished major renovations in this huge campus, a few meters from the Seine and in the heart of Paris. This contemporary campus is home to several thousand students, with public transportation nearby (bus and metro) and a large library inside the buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University also offers solutions for housing, such as financial assistance based on your income, or residences student. You will also find health services, restaurants and cafeteria. The Jussieu campus is located in the very chic 5th borough of Paris, not far from Saint-Germain, the Marais or the Natural History Museum.
As for the other schools or universities presented here, you will find many clubs or student associations to share your passion during your free hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;International Relation Service&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;International Relations Department &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;relations.internationales@upmc.fr&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d4882.281741830033!2d2.345138581530424!3d48.84995053159757!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0xf0b82c4672cb0c0!2sSorbonne+Universit%C3%A9+Campus+Pierre+et+Marie+Curie!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1565883734504!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="schools" /><summary type="html">Created from the merger of highly reputable universities UPMC and Paris Sorbonne, Sorbonne University is one of the biggest Parisian universities, with more than 55,000 students on its various campuses. The university offers several courses in computer science, in French or in English, for long or short periods.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IncubAlliance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/incuballiance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IncubAlliance" /><published>2019-03-25T21:45:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-25T21:45:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/incuballiance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/incuballiance">&lt;p&gt;Incubator of the &lt;a href=&quot;/parissaclay&quot;&gt;Paris-Saclay&lt;/a&gt; cluster since 2005, IncubAlliance’s main mission is to create bridges between startups, companies, labor and research experts within the Paris-Saclay campus, through support, training and hosting services for startups and education stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 Incubator Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;IncubAlliance&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Orsay, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏰 Size&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NC&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🔢 Startups incubated&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;404 incubated projects and 310 startups created&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🛍 The &lt;em&gt;“Petit plus”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Incubated startups work closely &lt;br /&gt;with universities and companies from Paris-Saclay HQ&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;NC&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located in the Paris-Saclay campus, a major hub of French innovation and the world’s 8th largest innovation cluster, IncubAlliance has been working for many years on the creation of innovative technology entrepreneurial projects at national and global level. In 2018, IncubAlliance incubated 42 new projects and 18 startups were created : that represents nearly 700 jobs for a survival rate of 95% (over 5 years), which is consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incubator is the result of many years of questioning about how higher education institutions (universities, engineering schools) should manage their postgraduate students who wanted to start their own business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By integrating the Paris-Saclay technology cluster, incubated startups work closely with students from neighboring schools or partners, and benefit from the expertise of 15% of French public and private research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/incuballiance-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IncubAlliance HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;support-for-startups&quot;&gt;Support for startups…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IncubAlliance program for startups is simple and accurate :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing a 35-day training program where experts help fine-tune one’s project, in workshop format, before a startup is definitively launched (called &lt;em&gt;GenesisLab&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing a 22-month support program, which includes coaching and group workshops, to steer startups toward their first product launch and sales (called &lt;em&gt;Incub22&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Financing projects throughout the entire incubation period to cover external and outsourced services.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Giving an incubation program certification (recognized by France).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offering shared or private accommodation for all teams in the Paris-Saclay HQ.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proposing collaborators and experts from Paris-Saclay universities, companies or laboratories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customized offers “Sur mesure” are of course available according to the needs of startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/incubators/img/incuballiance-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IncubAlliance HQ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-for-companies&quot;&gt;…And for companies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A developed company can also benefit from IncubAlliance’s advantages, such as :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing a privileged access to IncubAlliance’s services and the tech startup network.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Giving a complete excubation program specially designed for companies’ and institutions’ needs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing the GenesisLab program described above.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing a 8-day program with an introduction to technological entrepreneurship with a project under way (called &lt;em&gt;GenesisLight&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organizing meet-ups between startups, companies and research institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to all this, some programs are eligible for professional training financing solutions. The funding comes mainly from the European Union, the Île-de-France region and the Ministry of Higher Education of France.
Regarding the cost, it depends on the needs of startups but on average, it amounts to about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mon-incubateur.com/site_incubateur/incubateur/incuballiance-orsay&quot;&gt;7000€&lt;/a&gt; on the entire program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IncubAlliance Paris-Saclay&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; 86 Rue de Paris &lt;br /&gt; 91400 Orsay &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;contact@incuballiance.fr&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;+33 (0)1 77 93 21 00&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m14!1m8!1m3!1d10534.135779502953!2d2.1937061!3d48.6952746!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x78ee54de66ad73e!2sIncubAlliance!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1566744028290!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="incubators" /><summary type="html">Incubator of the Paris-Saclay cluster since 2005, IncubAlliance’s main mission is to create bridges between startups, companies, labor and research experts within the Paris-Saclay campus, through support, training and hosting services for startups and education stakeholders.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Epitech</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/epitech" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Epitech" /><published>2019-03-19T00:40:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:40:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/epitech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/epitech">&lt;p&gt;Epitech (also called European Institute of Technology) is a private Computer Science School with multiple campuses around the world and in Europe. The school offers computer courses to international and exchange students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Info Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🏢 School Name&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;École pour l’Informatique et les Nouvelles Technologies (EPITECH)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🌐 Location&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kremlin-Bicêtre, France&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;⚖️ Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Private Computer Science School&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;📆 Course Duration&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;🇪🇺 Erasmus Students&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Accepted&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;💵 Price&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6630€/year to 8580€/year (+ fees)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&quot;/epita&quot;&gt;EPITA&lt;/a&gt; computer science courses, Epitech is a private Computer Science School with numerous campuses in Europe and in the world. With more than 5000 students, Epitech uses self-study method, mainly in group projects and with very few hours of theoretical courses, all supervised by students from the higher grades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the students work from their personal computer and manage their own projects themselves, allowing them to gain autonomy. Unlike &lt;a href=&quot;/epita&quot;&gt;EPITA&lt;/a&gt;, theoretical scientific subjects such as mathematics or physics are not addressed during the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/epitech-photo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EPITECH campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;different-courses-for-different-profiles&quot;&gt;Different courses for different profiles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The school has several rooms equipped with powerful computers and the Epitech Innovation Hub offers a place with all the equipment and environment for enthusiasts to design innovative technological solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epitech offers two main courses. The first, the Bachelor program, takes place in 3 years. You learn the fundamentals using projects and “pools” (rush of programming) : you will have nearly 37 projects in 3 years, as well as management training courses.
At the end of the first 3 years, you can continue with the Advanced/Expert program (in 2 years, in addition to the first 3 years), you obtain a postgraduate degree &lt;em&gt;Expert in Information Technology&lt;/em&gt;, accredited level 1 by the National Commission for Vocational Certifications, with the possibility of doing a double degree with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isg.fr&quot;&gt;ISG&lt;/a&gt;, a French business school in Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/schools/img/epitech-photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;EPITECH campus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-influential-student-community&quot;&gt;An influential student community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epitech not only shares its campus with EPITA, but also hundreds of clubs. You will find video game, movies, programming, photo clubs and more. Epitech students also have access to a set of common services at the technology campus : network of associations, large cafeteria and more. Epitech  also enjoys privileged access to numerous student residences : 2 at the Kremlin-Bicêtre (including one on campus) and another in Villejuif (10-15 minutes from Paris). &lt;em&gt;Le +&lt;/em&gt; : The Val-de-Marne department offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.valdemarne.fr/a-votre-service/deplacement/transports/remboursement-de-la-carte-imagine-r&quot;&gt;refund of part of your transport costs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;🌐 &lt;em&gt;International Relation Service&lt;/em&gt; 🌐&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ksenia ANDREEVA&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Head of International Education Office &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;ksenia.andreeva@epitech.eu&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;+33 (0)1 84 07 14 12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d42014.45684238378!2d2.3332073273819454!3d48.84097834703352!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x47e6717ff972ae09%3A0x692326b123aa4d9b!2sEpitech+Paris!5e0!3m2!1sfr!2sfr!4v1565026117017!5m2!1sfr!2sfr&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Tom-Eliott</name></author><category term="schools" /><summary type="html">Epitech (also called European Institute of Technology) is a private Computer Science School with multiple campuses around the world and in Europe. The school offers computer courses to international and exchange students.</summary></entry></feed>